A Guide to the William H. Whyte papers FA272
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Projects and Research, 1
  - Pedestrian Traffic Studies, 1971-1992
    - Contracts, 1971-1977 (Box 14, Folder 235)
      Correspondence and notes concerning film contracts, including Whyte's 1971 proposal for a documentary series on street life.
    - Easements, Undated (Box 14, Folder 236)
      Includes an article on open space acquisition and preservation
    - Testimonies: Open Spaces, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 237)
      Includes testimony in support of the Community Recreation Enhancement Act of 1992.
  - Pedestrians: Research, 1968-1990
    Arranged alphabetically, then by type
    - Density Study: Peak Use Patterns at 630 Fifth Avenue, Parklet, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 238)
    - Density Study: Peak Use Patterns: Upper Broadway Benches, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 239)
    - Fifth Avenue Bench Study, 1974 May 2 (Box 15, Folder 240)
      - Fifth Avenue, North Bench and South Bench, 2014:FA272:023
      - West Bench, Rock Plaza Parklet, 2014:FA272:024
    - 630 Fifth Avenue: Use of the West Bench, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - Grand Central Station: Newsstands, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 242)
    - High Intensity Use Places, Undated (Box 15, Folder 243)
      - Exxon Rear Plaza - Use of Benches, 2014:FA272:025
    - Midtown Report: Lexington Avenue: Movement Analysis, Undated (Box 15, Folder 244)
    - Midtown Report: Original, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 245)
      File contains manuscript of Whyte's Midtown Development Study, 1980 February 29.
    - Midtown Report: Plaza Study: Gehl, Jan, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 246)
      Danish study of Pedestrian Activities (Mennesker til fods), with summary notes in English.
    - Midtown Report: Seagram Front Ledge, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 247)
      - Pedestrian Movements, 2014:FA272:026
    - New York Public Library and Topps Bar on 42nd Street: Pedestrian Street Activity, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 248)
    - Turnstile Counts: Lexington Avenue and 59th Street, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 249)
    - Pedestrians (Types)
      - Beggars, 1971-1985 (Box 15, Folder 250)
      - Entertainers, 1974-1985 (Box 15, Folder 251)
      - Food Vendors, 1978-1988 (Box 15, Folder 252)
      - "Husband Liberation": Male Chess Players on Bank Ledge at Madison Avenue and 57th Street, Undated (Box 15, Folder 253)
      - Merchandise Vendors, 1976-1986 (Box 15, Folder 254)
      - Messengers to Skilled Pedestrians, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 255)
      - Pedestrian Speeds, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 256)
      - Skilled Pedestrians, 1971-1986 (Box 15, Folder 257)
      - Social Pedestrian, Undated (Box 16, Folder 258)
      - Street People: First Amendment Rights, 1979-1985 (Box 16, Folder 259)
  - Penn Station/Madison Square Garden Study, 1973-1986
    - Boise: RFP Park, Undated (Box 16, Folder 260)
      Announcement of an urban design contest in Boise, to coincide with a visit from Whyte.
    - Cleveland: Standard Oil of Ohio, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 261)
      - Sohio Connector Study, Cleveland, OH, 2014:FA272:027
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 262)
    - IBM Building, Madison Avenue: Garden and Gallery Stairs Report, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 263)
    - IBM Building, Madison Avenue: Garden Research, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 264)
    - IBM Building, Madison Avenue: Sightings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 265)
    - IBM Building, Madison Avenue: Tabulations, Undated (Box 16, Folder 266)
    - IBM Building, Madison Avenue: Zoning, Building Code, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 267)
    - Kansas City: Allis Square, 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 268)
    - Missouri: St. Louis Project, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 269)
    - New York: Coenties Slip Park, 1983-1985 (Box 16, Folder 270)
    - New York Convention Center, 1980-1984 (Box 16, Folder 271)
      - Public galleria space, New York Convention Center, 2014:FA272:028
        Oversized plan.
    - New Jersey: Carnegie Center, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 272)
    - Penn Station: Charts, Tables, Undated (Box 16, Folder 273)
    - Penn Station: External Counts, Undated (Box 16, Folder 274)
    - Penn Station: Fruin, John, Study, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 275)
      Analysis of pedestrian circulation in proposed improvement plans for Penn Station.
    - Penn Station: Maps, Plans, Undated (Box 16, Folder 276)
      - Pedestrian flows, north sidewalk of 32nd Street, just east of Penta Hotel, 2014:FA272:029
      - Average hourly pedestrian flows, all exits LIRR-Penn Station, 2014:FA272:030
    - Penn Station: Pedestrian Counts, General, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 277)
      - Morning rush hour, Penn Station 7th Avenue entrance, 2014:FA272:031
      - Evening rush hour, Penn Station 7th Avenue entrance, 2014:FA272:032
      - Pedestrian flows, 2014:FA272:033
      - Pedestrian flows, 2014:FA272:034
    - Penn Station: Pedestrian Counts, Comparative, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 278)
    - Penn Station: Pedestrian Counts, Internal Worksheets, Undated (Box 17, Folder 279)
    - Penn Station: Report on Pedestrian Loads, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 280)
      - Pedestrian flows, north sidewalk of 32nd Street, just east of side entrance to Penta Hotel, 2014:FA272:035
    - Penn Station: Vehicular Counts, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 281)
    - Penn Station and Madison Square Garden: Notes, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 282)
    - Penn Station and Madison Square Garden: Report on Pedestrian Flows, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 283)
    - Pittsburgh: PPG Plaza Report, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 284)
      - Diagram - PPG Plaza, 2014:FA272:036
        Oversized diagram.
    - Princeton: Palmer Square, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 285)
    - Providence: Map, Undated (Box 17, Folder 286)
      - Diagram - Old Stone Plaza, Providence, RI, 2014:FA272:037
    - San Francisco Ferry Terminal, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 287)
      - Oversized plan, 2014:FA272:038
      - Oversized plan, 2014:FA272:039
    - Seattle: Washington Convention and Trade Center, General, 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 288)
    - Seattle: Washington Convention and Trade Center, Clippings, Notes, Memos, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 289)
    - Seattle: Westlake Project, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 290)
      - Plan - Westlake, Seattle, WA, 2014:FA272:040
      - Drawing - Westlake, Seattle, WA, 2014:FA272:041
        Oversized drawing.
    - Underground Concourses, 1973-1976 (Box 17, Folder 291)
  - Planning Flow Charts (Fort Worth Central Business District), Undated (Box 17, Folder 292)
  - Plaza Film, 1972-1983
    Many of these files were originally entitled "Pilot Film." Pilot Film or Plaza Film seems to have been a general working title for the film project resulting in The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces.
    - Chandigarh, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 293)
    - Hillier, Bill, Study, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 294)
      Reprint of "Space Syntax: A Different Urban Perspective," Architects' Journal, 1983 November 30.
    - Narration: Final, Undated (Box 17, Folder 295)
      Narration: The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces.
    - New York and Tokyo: Kon, Wajiro, Charts, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 296)
    - Pilot Film Annotation: Lead, Undated (Box 17, Folder 297)
      Annotation for pilot film lead of The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces.
    - Places in Plaza Film, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - Publicity, Undated (Box 17, Folder 299)
    - Sound Effects: Music, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 300)
    - Synopsis: Pilot 8, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 301)
    - WGBH Educational Foundation Distribution, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 302)
      For screening and distribution of The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces.
  - Plaza Report, 1973-1987
    - Basic Data: Counts, Measurements, Undated (Box 17, Folder 303)
    - City Planning Commission: Memos, Correspondence, 1972-1975, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 304)
      Includes Whyte's memo on proposed zoning changes for plaza and office building desing, 1973, and on the best and worst plazas in New York, 1974.
    - Footcandle Readings, Undated (Box 18, Folder 305)
    - Midtown: Urban Park, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 306)
      Announcement of hearing on proposed zoning amendments concerning urban open space and urban parks, 1974 September 23.
    - New York and Tokyo: A Study in Crowding, 1977-1987 (Box 18, Folder 307)
      Report by Whyte, August 30, 1977, and clippings.
    - Seagram Ledge Study, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 308)
      - Seagram's South Front Ledge, 2014:FA272:042
    - Seagram North Ledge: A Day in the Life, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 309)
      - Seagram's North Front Ledge, 2014:FA272:043
    - Seagram's Plaza: Analysis of Sightings, 1972-1987 (Box 18, Folder 310)
    - Space Comparisons, Undated (Box 18, Folder 311)
    - Street: General, 1981-1985 (Box 18, Folder 312)
      Includes notes on The Selling Street, The Physical street, and Whyte memo to the Bryant Park Restoration Corporation.
    - Street Walls: Notes, 1982-1986 (Box 18, Folder 313)
  - Plaza Studies, 1972-1983
    - General, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 314)
      File contains copy of Whyte's 1973 memo on proposed zoning changes for plaza and office building design.
    - International Plazas, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 315)
      Includes Whyte's presentations on "The Recurrent City" (1971); "Tokyo and New York: The Pedestrians' Environment" (Japan Society, 1982); and "The Rediscovery of the City" (Jerusalem, 1986).
    - Presentation Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 316)
    - Report: Microclimate, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 317)
    - Sightings, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 318)
    - Sightings, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 319)
    - Sightings, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 320)
      - Metropolitan Museum, 2014:FA272:044
    - Sightings, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 321)
    - Sunken Plazas, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 322)
    - Tabulations: Density and Use, Undated (Box 18, Folder 323)
  - President's Task Force for the Preservation of Natural Beauty, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 324)
  - Project Lock - Reston (Virginia), 1963-1967 (Box 19, Folder 325)
  - Regional, 1956-1990
    - Baltimore: Center Plaza, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 326)
    - Boston Redevelopment Authority: General, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 327)
      Correspondence, designs, and Whyte's observations concerning the Central Artery Project.
    - Boston Redevelopment Authority: Pedestrian Volumes, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 328)
      Whyte's memos on the Central Artery Project, including his notes on Pedestrian Volumes and other topics, and his Government Center Report.
    - Europe: Public Places, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 329)
      File consists of proofs of Public lIfe in Urban Places, by Suzanne H. Crowhurst Lennard and Henry L. Lennard.
    - Florida: Seaside Neighborhood, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 330)
    - Illinois: Park Forest, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 331)
    - Jerusalem: Walkway, Undated (Box 19, Folder 332)
    - New York: Density Statistics, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 333)
    - New York: Project for Public Spaces, Community Planning Center, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 334)
      File consists of List of Slides taken for the PPS Community Planning Center demo tape.
    - Seattle: NBBJ Project, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 335)
      Proposed Marathon Block office building development.
    - Washington, D.C.: National Capitol Planning Program, Urban Sprawl and Pre Year 2000 Plan, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 336)
      Includes outline for proposed Open Space Study.
    - Washington, D.C.: National Capitol Region, Open Space Planning: The Year 2000, 1962-1966 (Box 19, Folder 337)
    - Washington, D.C.: National Capitol Region, Open Space Planning: The Year 2000, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 338)
  - Return to the Agora, 1978-1987
    - Background, 1978-1987 (Box 19, Folder 339)
    - Cafe and Audience Space Ratios, Undated (Box 19, Folder 340)
    - In Praise of Short Term Plans, Undated (Box 19, Folder 341)
  - Rockefeller Plazas, 1972-1986
    - Greenacre Park: Base Vectors, Undated (Box 20, Folder 342)
    - Greenacre Park: Memos, Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 20, Folder 343)
    - Greenacre Park: Photographs, Undated (Box 20, Folder 344)
    - Greenacre Park: Sun Easement, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 345)
    - Greenacre Park: Sun Tables, Undated (Box 20, Folder 346)
    - Greenacre Park: Synagogue, 1972-1984 (Box 20, Folder 347)
    - Landmarks: General, 1981-1983 (Box 20, Folder 348)
      Includes correspondence concerning landmark status for Rockefeller Center.
    - Landmarks: Statutes, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 349)
    - Princeton University: Firestone Plaza, 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 350)
    - Princeton University: Herendeen, Ann, Firestone Plaza, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 351)
    - Princeton University: Rockefeller College, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 352)
  - Rose, Dan, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 353)
  - Scenic America, Inc., 1965-1989
    Biographical / Historical
    Until the spring of 1989, the organization was known as the Coalition for Scenic Beauty.
    - General, 1985-1989 (Box 20, Folder 354)
    - General, 1988-1989 (Box 20, Folder 355)
    - Davis, Hugh C., 1989 (Box 21, Folder 356)
      The file includes two papers by Davis: "A Classification for Scenic Roads," and "The Challenge of Scenic Roads."
    - Recreation Advisory Committee, 1965-1966, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 357)
    - Scenic Byways: History, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 358)
    - Scenic Byways: Legislation, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 359)
    - Scenic Byways: Memos, Notes, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 360)
    - Scenic Byways: Study, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 361)
    - Scenic Byways: Testimony, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 362)
  - Sensory Street: Research, 1974-1986
    - General, 1974-1981 (Box 21, Folder 363)
    - Background, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 364)
    - Doors, 1979-1986 (Box 21, Folder 365)
    - Gottdiener, M.: Shopping Mall Jargon, Undated (Box 21, Folder 366)
    - Hand Movements, Undated (Box 21, Folder 367)
    - Lexington Avenue: The Lighthouse, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 368)
    - Lexington Avenue: Newsstand Behavior, Subway Behavior, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 369)
    - Lexington Avenue: Notes on Street People, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 370)
    - Lexington Avenue: Social Notes, Memos, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 371)
    - Lexington Avenue: Street Vendors, Handbill Passers, 1972-1974 (Box 21, Folder 372)
    - Outline, Notes, Undated (Box 21, Folder 373)
    - Pedestrian Flow: Time Lapse, Beggar Studies, Undated (Box 21, Folder 374)
    - Retailing, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 375)
    - Schmoozing: First National City Bank, Undated (Box 21, Folder 376)
    - Second Storyness, 1978-1982 (Box 21, Folder 377)
    - Shopping Streets, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 378)
    - Sound, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 379)
    - Theater Queues, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 380)
    - Trash, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 381)
      - Steps and Entrances, 1980-1984
        - Physical Entrances: Background, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 395)
        - Plazas, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 396)
        - Steps: General, Undated (Box 22, Folder 397)
        - Steps: Background, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 398)
    - Walkway Widths, 1978-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 382)
    - Window Shopping, 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 383)
  - Social Life of the Street, 1968-1980
    - Block Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 384)
    - Gehl, Jan, Studies, 1968-1976 (Box 21, Folder 385)
    - Hands, Feet, and Gestures: Annotated, Undated (Box 22, Folder 386)
    - Herendeen, Ann: Street Conversations, 53rd Street and Fifth Avenue: Hellos, Good-byes, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 387)
    - Map: Schmoozing Locations, Undated (Box 22, Folder 388)
    - Notes on 101st Street, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 389)
    - 100% Conversations: Map, Undated (Box 22, Folder 390)
    - 100% Conversations: Schmoozing Reciprocals: Background, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 391)
    - 100% Conversations: Schmoozing Reciprocals: Report copies, Undated (Box 22, Folder 392)
    - Street Conversations: 48th Street and Madison Avenue, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 393)
    - Street Conversations: 50th Street and Fifth Avenue: Analysis, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 394)
  - Street Life Project, 1971-1988
    - General, 1971-1985 (Box 22, Folder 399)
    - Articles, 1974-1989 (Box 22, Folder 400)
      Includes articles written about Whyte
    - Expenditures (Cumulative Record), 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 401)
    - Expenses, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 402)
    - Expenses, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 403)
    - Expenses, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 404)
    - Funding, 1971-1976 (Box 23, Folder 405)
    - Film Project: Municipal Art Society of New York, 1971-1980 (Box 23, Folder 406)
    - Fund for the City of New York, 1973-1976 (Box 23, Folder 407)
    - Graham Foundation, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 408)
    - National Endowment for the Arts: General, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 409)
    - National Endowment for the Arts: Grant Recognition, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 410)
    - National Recreation and Park Association: Budget Records, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 411)
    - National Recreation and Park Association: Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 23, Folder 412)
    - National Recreation and Park Association: Narrative Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 413)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1976-1980 (Box 23, Folder 414)
  - Street People: Research, 1971-1986
    - Bag Ladies, Derelicts, 1973-1986 (Box 23, Folder 415)
    - Characters, 1971-1985 (Box 23, Folder 416)
    - Crime, General, 1972-1985 (Box 23, Folder 417)
    - Dope Dealers, 1977-1983 (Box 23, Folder 418)
    - Homeless, 1976-1986 (Box 23, Folder 419)
    - Night Life, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 420)
    - Older People, 1971-1976 (Box 23, Folder 421)
    - Security, 1976-1981 (Box 23, Folder 422)
    - Street Kids and Nomads, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 423)
    - Street Theater, 1971-1979 (Box 23, Folder 424)
    - Three Card Monte, 1977-1979 (Box 23, Folder 425)
    - Whores, 1975-1981 (Box 23, Folder 426)
  - Suburban Centers, 1977-1987
    - Rate 1, 1981-1987 (Box 24, Folder 427)
    - Revitalization: Centrality, 1977-1987 (Box 24, Folder 428)
  - Sun and Light: Research, 1967-1987
    - General, 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 429)
    - Clippings, 1986-1987 (Box 24, Folder 430)
    - Dallas, Tokyo, 1983-1985 (Box 24, Folder 431)
    - Japan, Undated (Box 24, Folder 432)
    - Microclimate Study: General, 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 433)
    - Microclimate Study: City Environmental Quality Review, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 434)
    - New York City, Undated (Box 24, Folder 435)
    - Notes: General, 1967-1980 (Box 24, Folder 436)
    - Notes: Building Heights, 1974-1981 (Box 24, Folder 437)
    - Philadelphia, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 438)
    - San Francisco, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 439)
  - "Think" Files, 1959-1981
    - Big Thinking, 1959-1967 (Box 24, Folder 440)
    - Conservationist Thinking: Pure Malthusians, 1967-1970 (Box 24, Folder 441)
    - Think Stuff, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 442)
    - Who's In Charge?, 1964-1966 (Box 24, Folder 443)
  - Udall, Stewart, Book Comments, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 444)
    Whyte read a draft of "Cities in Trouble: Frederick Law Olmsted," which forms a chapter of Udall's 1963 book, Quiet Crisis.
  - Union Station: Presentation, Undated (Box 25, Folder 445)
  - Vehicular Studies, 1963-1980
    - General, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 446)
    - Machine Count: East 53rd Street, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 447)
    - Machine Count: Lexington Avenue, General, 1963-1976 (Box 25, Folder 448)
    - Machine Count: Lexington Avenue Cars, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 449)
    - Machine Count: Lexington Avenue Traffic Department, Undated (Box 25, Folder 450)
    - Machine Count: Lexington Avenue Trucks, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 451)
    - Parking: Fifth Avenue and Madison Avenue, 1977-1980 (Box 25, Folder 452)
    - Parking: Lexington Avenue: 42nd Street to 61st Street, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 453)
    - Parking: Lexington Avenue: Analysis and Charts, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 454)
      - Parking at Doctor's Row, 2014:FA272:045
      - Chart - untitled, 2014: FA272:046
    - Parking: Lexington Avenue: Double-Parking Study, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 455)
      - Lexington Avenue Vehicle Study, 2014:FA272:047
    - Parking: Lexington Avenue: Spot Checks of Parking Licenses, Repeaters, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 456)
    - Parking: Privileged Parking Lawsuit, 1970-1976 (Box 25, Folder 457)
    - Parking: Time Lapse Studies of Diurnal Patterns, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 458)
      - Parking Patterns: Lane 1, Lexington/60th-61st, 2014:FA272:048
    - Parking versus Pedestrians: Midtown, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 459)
    - Pedestrian - Vehicular Charts, Undated (Box 25, Folder 460)
      - Vehicular Traffic on Lexington Avenue, 2014:FA272:049
    - Pedestrian - Vehicular Counts: Lexington Avenue, Update, Undated (Box 25, Folder 461)
    - Report: Lexington Avenue, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 462)
      - Vehicular Traffic on Lexington Avenue, 2014:FA272:050
    - Traffic Count: Bowery Site, Undated (Box 25, Folder 463)
    - Type of Vehicle Study: Madison Avenue, 51st Street - 52nd Street, Undated (Box 25, Folder 464)
    - Vehicular Flow: Broadway and Seventh Avenue Proposal, Undated (Box 25, Folder 465)
    - Vehicular Flow: Lexington Avenue Buses, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 466)
    - Vehicular Flow: Lexington Avenue Taxis, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 467)
    - Vehicular Flow: Lexington Avenue Worksheets, 1974 September (Box 25, Folder 468)
    - Vehicular Flow: Lexington Avenue Worksheets, 1974 October (Box 26, Folder 469)
    - Vehicular Flow: Taxis and Arrivals, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 470)
  - Workprints, 1971-1978
    - 50 - 99, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 471)
    - 100 - 149, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 472)
    - 150 - 200, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 473)
    - 200 - 250, 400s, Undated (Box 26, Folder 474)
    - Log, 1971-1978 (Box 26, Folder 475)
- Personal, 2
  The Personal series contains speeches or outlines of speeches given by Whyte, writings about Whyte, and writings by Whyte. The writings by Whyte include several articles for Fortune magazine and other publications as well as drafts of chapters in a book Whyte hoped to write on his experiences in the Marine Corps in the 1940s.
  The Speeches section in this series is also worth noting. Many of the speeches outline and provide insight into Whyte's philosophies and the conclusions he draws as a result of his research. Clippings and articles about Whyte can also be found in the Personal series.
  Of particular note, the Personal series actually contains very little information about Whyte's personal life. There are few correspondence files and no journal entries. However, the Writing by Whyte section of this series gives glimpses of Whyte's personality. Manuscripts on the Marine Corps School, which he wrote for an unrealized memoir, contain Whyte's reminiscences on his time in the military. Additionally, Whyte's plays and poems, such as Toffenetti Spaghetti, reveal his creativity and sense of humor.
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1974-1984 (Box 26, Folder 476)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 477)
  - Professional Invitations, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 478)
  - Speeches, 1966-1990
    - Speaking Engagements
      Files contain speeches, notes, and correspondence relating to speaking engagements.
      - 1966-1969 (Box 26, Folder 479)
      - 1973-1979 (Box 26, Folder 480)
      - 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 481)
      - 1984 (Box 27, Folder 482)
      - 1985 (Box 27, Folder 483)
      - 1986 (Box 27, Folder 484)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 485)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 486)
      - Undated (Box 27, Folder 487)
      - Notes, Drafts, Undated (Box 28, Folder 488)
    - B.Y. Morrison Memorial Lecture: The War Against the Street, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 489)
    - Duke University Seminar: Thoughts on Methodology, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 490)
      The paper is entitled "Some Thoughts on Observation," with a penciled heading "Busted Hypotheses."
    - Easements, 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 491)
      Whyte's speech, entitled "Easements: Limitations and Potentials," was prepared for the Symposium on the Maine Coast, at Bowdoin College, October 21, 1966.
    - Easements: Speech and Outline, 1974 March 9 (Box 28, Folder 492)